Guide to the Frank Lyon Polk Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Frank Lyon Polk papers
1883-1942
MS 656
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
28
(63 boxes, 5 folios)
The papers consist of correpondence, letterbooks, documents, diaries, subject files and other materials documenting the personal life and professional career of Frank Lyon Polk. The bulk of the material relates to Polk's Department of State service and includes correspondence with political figures, letterpress copybooks (1915-1917), and diaries (1915-1920). Materials relating to the American Commission to Negotiate Peace and the League of Nations are also included.
Polk, Frank L. (Frank Lyon), 1871-1943
Conditions Governing Access
Permission of the head of Manuscripts and Archives is necessary to examine boxes 64-67.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elizabeth Polk and her children, 1943.
Existence and Location of Copies
Diary is available on microfilm (3 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM47.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, 1898-1942. II. Diaries, 1915-1920. III. Subject Files, 1912-1921. IV. Chronological Files, 1915-1919. V. Politics and Memorabilia, 1883-1941.
Scope and Contents
The Frank L. Polk Papers consist of twenty-two linear feet of correspondence, diaries, memoranda, telephone logs, memorabilia, and miscellaneous printed and mimeographed-material. They are arranged in five series:
I. Correspondence
II. Diaries
III. Subject Files
IV. Chronological Files
V. Politics and Memorabilia
Most of the papers in Series I and all the papers in Series II-IV are related to Polk's service as Counselor and Under Secretary in the State Department. Series V spans most of his life but relates mainly to his diplomatic service and to his political and civic activities in New York. There are only a few items related to his practice of law.
The Polk Papers were reprocessed in 1978 because the original arrangement and description by Charles Seymour and his staff had proved unsatisfactory to many researchers. The principal change was to separate most of the correspondence from the miscellaneous papers that are now arranged by subject (roughly as Seymour left them) in Series III. "Partial Index to Series I" is a listing by subject of correspondents whose letters have been removed from Seymour's subject arrangement.
Series I, Correspondence, is related mainly to Polk's service in the State Department. The major correspondents include Gordon Auchincloss, Ray Stannard Baker, Henry Bruère, Frederic R. Coudert, Sir Richard Crawford, John W. Davis, Henry P. Fletcher, David R. Francis, Norman Hapgood, Edward M. House, Jean Jusserand, Robert Lansing, Irwin B. Laughlin, Clarence H. Mackay, Walter Hines Page, William Phillips, Sir Cecil Arthur Spring Rice, Frederic N. Watriss, and Woodrow Wilson. Most of the letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent, but there are also letterbooks containing copies of outgoing letters in chronological order from 1915 to 1917.
Notwithstanding the modification of Charles Seymour's arrangement of the papers, there are still some letters filed by subject in Series III. The series description for Series I and the introduction to the "Partial Index to Series I" explain how to find correspondence by writer and by subject.
There is also a small amount of correspondence in Series V, consisting mainly of personal letters, congratulations on Polk's various appointments, and exchanges with historians about events in World War I diplomacy.
Series II, Diaries, spans from 1915 to 1920. It consists partly of memoranda of conversations with representatives of foreign governments. Copies of individual memoranda were circulated within the State Department, and some of these copies are mixed with other papers in Series III.
Series III, Subject Files, consists of memoranda, correspondence, and miscellaneous papers spanning mainly from 1915 to 1920. Polk himself created very few of these items; the series consists rather of papers submitted to him and papers circulated among State Department staff. There are a great many carbon and mimeographed copies, some of which bear handwritten notations.
Series IV, Chronological Files, consists of transcripts of telephone conversations and several sequences of State Department mimeographed materials. The transcripts resulted from government wiretapping between 1915 and 1917.
Series V, Politics and Memorabilia, consists of certificates, clippings, photographs, routine correspondence, mementoes, and miscellaneous papers related to Polk's education, military and diplomatic service, and political and civic activities.
Biographical / Historical
Frank Lyon Polk was born in New York City on September 13, 1871. He graduated from Yale College (B.A., 1894) and Columbia University Law School (LL.D., 1897). Polk served on a variety of New York City boards and commissions (1906-1913) and as Corporation Counsel (1914-1915). He also served in the Department of State as Counselor (1915-1919), Acting Secretary of State (1918-1919), and Under Secretary of State (1919-1920). Polk headed the American Mission to Negotiate Peace (1919) and managed the 1924 Democratic presidential convention campaign of John W. Davis. Polk died in New York City on February 7, 1943. Here are some principal events in his public and personal life:
1871 Sep 13 born in New York City to William M. and Ida A. (Lyon) Polk
1890 graduated from Groton School
1894 graduated from Yale College
1897 graduated from Columbia University Law School
1897-1900 served as clerk in the law firm of Evarts, Choate and Beaman
1898-1899 served as Captain and assistant on the Quartermaster Staff of General Ernst's Brigade
1900 formed the legal partnership that became Alexander, Watriss and Polk
1906-1907 served on the New York City Board of Education
1907-1909 served on and presided over the Municipal Civil Service Commission of the City of New York
1908 married Elizabeth Sturgis Potter
1911-1913 served as treasurer of the Bureau of Municipal Research
1913 supported the candidacy of John Purroy Mitchel for Mayor of New York
1914-1915 served as Corporation Counsel of the City of New York
1915-1919 served as Counselor of the State Department
1918 Apr - Sep suffered from a nervous disorder
1918 Dec - 1919 Jul served as Acting Secretary of State
1919 Jun - 1920 Jun served as Under Secretary of State
1919 Jul - Dec headed the American Mission to Negotiate Peace in Paris
1920 formed the legal partnership that became Davis Polk Wardwell Gardiner and Reed
1924 managed John W. Davis's pre-convention and convention campaign for the Democratic nomination to the presidency
1943 Feb 7 died in New York City
For additional information about Polk's honors and appointments, see the Yale University Obituary Record of Graduates, 1942-1943. For brief assessments of Polk's career, see John W. Davis's memorial in the Association of the Bar of the City of New York Year Book, 1944, and Lawrence E. Gelfand's article in the Dictionary of American Biography, 1941-1945.
Adriatic question; Armed Forces; Armenian question; Law; World War, 1914-1918; New York (N.Y.); New York (State); United States -- Foreign relations -- 1913-1921; United States -- Politics and government; Diplomats; Lawyers; Adamson, Robert; Anderson, Chandler P. (Chandler Parsons), 1866-1936; Atherton, Gertrude Franklin Horn, 1857-1948; Auchincloss, Gordon, 1886-1943; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946; Bernstorff, Johann Heinrich, Graf von, 1862-1939; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Bruère, Henry; Carey, Francis King, 1858-1944; De Cartier de Marchienne, Émile, 1871-1946; Clemenceau, Georges, 1841-1929; Coudert, Frederic R. (Frederic René), 1871-1955; Creel, George, 1876-1953; Davis, John W. (John William), 1873-1955; Debevoise, Thomas M., 1874-1957; Dix, William C.; Dresel, Ellis Loring, 1865-1925; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959; Egan, Martin, 1872-1938; Egan, Maurice Francis, 1852-1924; Elkus, Abram I., 1867-1947; Fletcher, Henry Prather, 1873-1959; Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine), 1883-1972; Gama, Domicio da, 1862-1925; Garrison, Lindley M. (Lindley Miller), 1864-1932; Garvan, Francis P. (Francis Patrick), 1875-1937; Gerard, James W. (James Watson), 1823-1900; Glynn, Martin Henry, 1871-1924; Godson, William Frederick Holford, 1896-; Gregory, Thomas Watt, 1861-1933; Grew, Joseph C. (Joseph Clark), 1880-1965; Hapgood, Norman, 1868-1937; Harrison, Leland, 1883-1951; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; Houston, David Franklin, 1866-1940; Jusserand, J. J. (Jean Jules), 1855-1932; Kelley, Francis C.; Lane, Franklin K.; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; Long, Breckinridge, 1881-1958; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; Metz, Herman A., 1867-1934; Mezes, Sidney Edward, 1863-1931; Miller, David Hunter, 1875-1961; Palmer, A. Mitchell (Alexander Mitchell), 1872-1936; Phillips, William, 1878-1968; Polk, Frank L. (Frank Lyon), 1871-1943; Polk, Ida Ashe Lyon; Reading, Rufus Daniel Isaacs, 1st Marquis, 1889-1960; Redfield, William Cox, 1858-1932; Riaño y Gayangos, Juan, 1865-1939; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Rowe, L. S. (Leo Stanton), 1871-1946; Shaw, Gardiner Howland, 1893-1965; Spring Rice, Cecil, Sir, 1859-1918; Tardieu, André, 1876-1945; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954; Warren, Charles, 1868-1954; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Woolsey, Lester Hood, 1877-1961; United States. Department of State; Haight, Sandford, & Smith; League of Nations; United States. Council of National Defense; Yale University -- Students; Paris Peace Conference ( 1919-1920)
- Correspondence, 1898-(1915-1920)-1942; Series I; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  There are two sequences: loose letters, arranged alphabetically (boxes 1-14); and letterbooks, arranged chronologically (boxes 15-16).
  The folder listing for this series has cross-references not only to other correspondents in this series, but also to folders with descriptive headings arranged by subject in Series III. Many letters and memoranda that are filed in Series III do not, however, have cross-references in the folder listing for Series I. The letters and memoranda in Series III that do not have cross-references in the folder listing for Series I fall mainly under three headings: routine communications by U.S. and foreign government officials; all communications by foreign government officials that are filed under the names of their countries; and requests for assistance in getting passports (which are filed chronologically in Series III, Passports ).
  "Partial Index to Series I" is a subject guide to correspondence in this series.
  *An asterisk indicates folders of ten or more items.
  - Abele, C. A.
    General note
    See: Poland, box 32, folder 628
  - Abraham, Edgar, 1919 September - October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ackerman, Carl W., 1918 Jan, March
    See also: Gordon Auchincloss (1918 Aug 27-28), box 1, folder 17 See also: Abram I. Elkus (1918 Feb 5), box 5, folders 167-168
  - (*) Adamson, Robert, 1914 Jan, 1917 June - November (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adee, Alvey A., 1916 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
    See also: Turkey, box 36, folders 830-831
  - Aguilar, Candido, 1919 August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albert, Heinrich F., 1916 November - 1917 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, Henry T., 1919 October - Nov, 1920 Jun, 1924 July (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allenby, Edmund Henry Hyman, 1st viscount
    See: John Finley, box 5, folder 176
  - Allied Printing Trades Council of Greater New York
    See: Peter J. Brady, box 2, folder 69
  - American Bar Association, 1918 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Committee for the Independence of Armenia
    See: Vahan Cardashian, box 3, folder 94 See: James W. Gerard, box 6, folder 202
  - American Consular Association, 1919 March - May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Labor
    See: Labor, box 28, folder 408 See: Labor, box 28, folder 412
  - American International Corporation
    See: George J. Baldwin, box 2, folder 37
  - American Jewish Committee
    See: Louis Marshall, box 10, folder 348
  - American Metal Company
    See: Julian B. Beaty, box 2, folder 43 See: Henry Bruére, box 3, folders 77-78
  - American Over-seas Corporation
    See: Trade, box 35, folder 782-798
  - American Red Cross, 1917 Jun, 1918 January - Jul, 1919 October (Box 1, Folder 5)
    See also: Edward W. Ryan, box 12, folder 423 See also: Albania, box 22, folder 90 See also: Albania, box 22, folder 92 See also: Rumania, box 32, folder 645 See also: Russia, box 33, folders 701-702 See also: Ukraine, box 36, folder 838
  - American-Russian Chamber of Commerce
    See: Samuel Reading Bertron, box 2, folder 49, 1919 Apr 19 - May 22
  - American Smelting and Refining Company
    See: Mexico, box 29, folder 484
  - American Trading Company, 1921 January (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Transatlantic Company
    See: Philip W. Herzog, box 7, folders 252-253 See: Perley Morse, box 10, folder 362 See: R. G. Wagner, box 13, folder 465 See: Shipping, box 34, folder 716
  - Amis de la France, Les
    See: Henry Soulié, box 12, folder 440
  - Anderson, Chandler P.
    - (*), 1915 December - 1916 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (*), 1917 March - 1918 August (Box 1, Folder 7)
      General
      See also: Gordon Auchincloss (1918 Jun 29), box 1, folder 17
      See also: Ricardo Fernández Guardia, box 5, folder 174
  - Anderson, Henry B., 1919 April - May (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, Henry W., 1919 October (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, John C., 1913 Apr, 1916 November - December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, Larz, 1917 August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anderson, T. Hart, Jr., 1917 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrade, C., Jr., 1917 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrews, A. B., 1918 October (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Andujar, Anthony, 1917 March (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1927 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Murphy Democrats
    See: Frederic R. Coudert (1915 Dec 14), box 4, folder 113, 1915 Dec 14
  - Antonsanti, Frank, 1913 Jul, 1915 October (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aravantinos, Panos, 1917 May, July (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Armour, J. Ogden, 1916 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Armour, Norman, 1919 August - November (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Armour and Company
    See: Charles J. Faulkner, Jr., box 5, folder 173
  - Arnavon, Jacques, 1919 August (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arnold, Julian, 1916 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Asquith, Emma Alice Margaret, 1922 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Associated Press, 1917 February - May (Box 1, Folder 13)
    See also: Frank B. Noyes, box 10, folder 370 See also: R. G. Wagner, box 13, folder 465
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1921 March (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - (*) Atherton, Gertrude Franklin (Mrs. George H. B.), 1917 October - 1918 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Atlantic Gulf Oil Corporation
    See: Frederic N. Watriss (1920 Jan 2), box 13, folders 479-480, 1920 Jan 2
  - Atlantic Refining Company
    See: Thomas F. Logan, box 9, folder 330
  - Auchincloss, Gordon
    - (*), 1916 Jun, Dec; 1917 March - May, August (Box 1, Folder 15)
      See also: Banking Transactions with the Enemy, box 23, folder 149
    - (*), 1917 September - December (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - (*), 1918 Jun, August (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 487
      See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 489
    - (*), 1918 September - November (Box 1, Folder 18)
      See also: Netherlands, box 31, folder 561
    - 1918 December - 1919 March 12, 1919 March 18 - May (Box 1, Folder 19-22)
    - (*), 1919 June - Sep, 1924 July (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Avalow, ____
    See: Norman Hapgood (1919 Nov 3), box 7, folders 233-238, 1919 Nov 3
  - Avezzana, Camillo Romano, baron, 1920 February - March (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bacon, Selden, 1918 August (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baker, Jessie I. (Mrs. Ray Stannard), 1918 August (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - (*) Baker, Newton D., 1917 February - 1918 March, 1920 Jun, 1921 March, 1925 March - Apr, 1935 July - 1936 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
    See also: Woodrow Wilson (1920 Mar 18), box 14, folders 508-516
  - Baker, Ray Stannard
    - 1918 February - August (Box 1, Folder 26-31)
    - 1918 September - 1919 March (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    - (*), 1926 June, 1930 June - September, 1935 Dec, 1937 September - November (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1938 Jan, October - December (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bakhmeteff, Boris A., 1923 April (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Balch, Emily Greene, 1916 August - September (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Baldwin, George J., 1917 May (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Baldwin, Henry DeForest, 1914 January (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Baldwin, Joseph C., Jr., 1919 February - March (Box 2, Folder 37)
    See also: Martin Egan (1918 Apr 23) box 5, folders 161-162
  - Balfour, Arthur James, 1917 May; 1919 Aug, Nov; 1930 February (Box 2, Folder 38)
    See also: Near East, box 31, folder 543
  - Bandholtz, Harry Hill, 1919 September - November (Box 2, Folder 38)
    See also: Hungary, box 27, folder 364 See also: Rumania, box 32, folder 650 See also: Rumania, box 32, folder 655
  - (*) Barclay, Colville, 1915 December - 1917 Mar; 1918 Jan, July - December; 1919 June - August (Box 2, Folder 39)
    See also: Woodrow Wilson (1918 Aug 2), box 14, folders 503-505
  - [Barnes, Charles?]
    See: Czechoslovakia, box 24, folder 217
  - Barney, Hiram, 1917 July (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Barondess, Joseph, 1919 January (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Barrett, John, 1917 Jul, 1920 June (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Barsaum, Sévèrius Aphram, 1919 November (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Barton, Carlyle
    See: Cuba, box 24, folder 212
  - Barton, James Levi, 1917 December (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1917 February, 1918 January - February (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bassompièrre, Alfred de, 1919 August (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Battle, George Gordon, 1915 Sep, 1917 May - August (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Baylor, Eugene H., 1917 November (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bayne, Hugh A., 1919 January - 1920 January (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Beard, Charles A.
    See: Passports, box 31, folder 591
  - (*) Beaty, Julian B., 1917 May - October, 1918 October - November (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Bedle, J[oseph?] D., 1915 December (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Beeckman, Robert Livingston, 1917 September - October (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Beer, George Louis
    See: American Mission, box 22, folder 99
  - Beers, Lucius Hart, 1920 February (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Bell, George H., 1917 April - May (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Belt, John W., 1917 Jul, 1919 March (Box 2, Folder 45)
    See also: Norman Hapgood (1916 Nov 16), box 7, folder 231
  - Bennet, William S., 1916 Jun, 1917 July - October (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Bennett, James Gordon
    See: Selden Bacon, box 1, folder 24
  - Benson, William Sheperd, 1916 Oct, 1919 July (Box 2, Folder 46)
    See also: Armistice, box 22, folder 119
  - Beresford, Charles William de la Poer Beresford, 1st baron
    See: Walter Hines Page (1917 Jan 25), box 11, folders 375-381
  - Bergson, Henri (as President of the Association des "French Homes")
    See: Edouard de Billy (1918 Nov 2), box 2, folder 53
  - Bernard, Judae and Company, 1915 November (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Bernheimer, Charles L., 1915 October - Nov, 1917 October (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Bernstein, Herman, 1918 December - 1919 February (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - (*) Bernstorff, Johann-Heinrich von, count, 1915 Sep; 1916 Apr; 1917 January - Feb, December (Box 2, Folder 48)
    See also: H. E. Hooper, box 8, folder 263 See also: Edward M. House (1916 Apr 28, Oct 9), box 8, folders 268-269,
  - Bernstrom, R.
    See: Wilhelm August Ferdinand Ekengren, box 5, folder 165
  - Bertron, Samuel Reading, 1919 March - May, 1920 June (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Berwind-White Coal Company
    See: Germany, box 25, folder 278
  - Bethell, Hugh Keppel, 1919 July (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Betts, L. Fred Holbrook, 1917 November (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bibesco, Elizabeth Asquith (Mrs. Antoine), 1922 December (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bible, Howard Wiswall, 1915 November - December (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Biddle, John, 1917 November (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Bielaski, A. Bruce, 1915 Dec; 1916 Mar, Aug; 1917 May (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bien-Être du Blessé, Le
    See: Gertrude Franklin Atherton, box 1, folder 14
  - Billings, Sherrard, 1917 December (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Billy, Edouard de (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - 1917 October - 1918 June (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - (*), 1918 July - November (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Birch, Thomas Howard, 1919 September (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bishop, Francis C., 1916 June (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bissell, Leslie Dayton
    See: Harry A. Garfield, box 6, folder 197
  - Björkman, Edwin, 1919 March (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Blair, Clinton Ledyard, 1918 January (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Blair, William McCormick, 1917 November - December (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Blair, Woodbury, 1917 May (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Blanquet, Aurelio, 1919 March (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Bliss, Cornelius N., Jr., 1915 December (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Bliss, Robert Woods, 1917 August - Sep, 1918 August, 1920 March (Box 2, Folder 56)
    See also: René Viviani, box 13, folder 463
  - Bliss, Tasker Howard
    - 1916 Nov; 1918 Mar, October (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - 1919 July - September (Box 2, Folder 58)
      See also: James G. Harbord (1919 Sep 13, 15), box 7, folder 239
      See also: Adriatic Question, box 21, folder 20
    - 1919 October 12-18 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      See also: Allen W. Dulles (1919 Oct 24), box 5, folder 157
      See also: Rumania, box 32, folder 656
    - 1919 October 21 - November 15, 1919 November 19 - 1920 Mar, 1923 October (Box 2, Folder 60-61)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1920 April (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Block, Rudolph, 1917 March - December (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Bohemian National Alliance, 1917 July (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Boissevain, Eugen, 1916 October (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Boissevain, G. Louis, 1917 October - November (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Boissevain and Company, 1919 August (Box 2, Folder 63)
    See also: Lindley M. Garrison, box 6, folder 198 See also: A. G.[?] Miller, box 10, folder 353
  - Boldt, George C., 1916 May (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Bolling, John Randolph, 1917 February (Box 2, Folder 64)
    See also: Edith B. G. Wilson ([1924 Feb 4?]), box 13, folder 486
  - Bonilla, Policarpo, 1919 August (Box 2, Folder 64)
    See also: Luis Suazo, box 13, folder 451
  - Bonillas, Ygnacio, 1917 July - Aug, 1918 Mar, November (Box 2, Folder 65)
    See also: Henry, Bruére (1917 Nov 2), box 3, folder 80
  - Bonsal, Henrietta Morris (Mrs. Stephen), 1919 March (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Bonsal, Stephen, 1916 September - October (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Borgfeldt (Geo.) and Co., 1915 Oct, 1917 May, 1918 June (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Borglum, [John] Gutzon [de la Molte]
    See: Cuba, box 24, folder 214
  - Bosler, William D., 1917 June - July (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Boston Evening Transcript, 1919 June - July (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Bourchier, James David, 1919 August - September (Box 2, Folder 67)
    See also: Greece, box 26, folder 339
  - (*) Bowman, Isaiah, 1919 December - 1920 May (Box 2, Folder 68)
    See also: Adriatic Question, box 21, folders 57-71 See also: Central Europe, box 24, folder 187
  - (*) Brady, Peter J., 1915 October - 1916 August (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Brambilla, Giuseppe, 1919 September (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Brancker, William Sefton, 1918 May - July (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Brandegee, Frank B., 1915 December - 1916 Feb, 1919 April (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Brandeis, Louis D.
    See: Woodrow Wilson (1916 Aug 9), box 14, folders 488-494
  - Braniff, Oscar J.
    See: Mexico, box 28, folder 442
  - Breckinridge, Henry, 1916 August (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Breckinridge, James C.
    See: Preston McGoodwin, box 10, folder 338
  - Bride, William W., 1916 Mar, April (Box 2, Folder 70)